So now that we have a prototype, we're moving to the validation stage, right?
现在我们有了自己的原型 需要进入到确认阶段 对吧？
>> That's right.
是的
The validation stage answers the hardest question in product design.
确认阶段回答了产品设计中最难的一个问题
The hardest question in product design is
产品设计中最难的一个问题是
how do you know if your work is any good?
我如何知道产品好不好呢？
>> Okay, that's an important question.
这是个重要的问题
>> [LAUGH] It's very important.
是的 非常重要
How we answer this question has three different stages.
我们回答这个问题也是分三个阶段
At Google we use something that we call triple validation.
在 Google 我们采用的是三重确认
Just like in the beginning we looked at a problem from the perspective of
就像在一开始 我们看问题从三个角度出发
business, technology, and users, at the end
业务、技术、用户 在最后
we want to validate the solution from the same three touch points.
我们也同样要从这三个点出发确认解决方案
The most important opinion, and the most important votes and
最重要的观点 最重要的投票和确认
validation, is that of the users.
还是来自用户
So the critical piece not to miss is the opportunity to
所以必不可少的就是要找寻机会
test your prototype with your users.
让用户测试原型
We recommend sprinters and the sprint lead recruit users from the very
我们建议冲刺者和冲刺领导从一开始就找寻用户
beginning of the sprint, so they know that, at the end, the users are coming.
确保在最后有用户能够过来
>> Right.
是的
>> And they have to prepare for it, and
他们必须要为此做准备
else, all the efforts that they have spent in prototyping could go to waste
如果他们不知道原型是否能解决用户的需求
because they don't actually know if this is solving the needs the users have.
那他们在原型设计上耗费的努力就是白搭的
So meeting the users at the beginning is useful to learn their needs, and
所以 一开始见用户为了理解他们的需求
meeting them at the end is crucial in order to test.
而在最后见客户是为了测试 这是至关重要的
This type of test is called usability test or Cognitive Walkthrough.
这种测试类型称为易用性测试或认知走查
It allows you to put the products or the early prototype in
你可以将产品或早期原型
the hands of a user and watch them walkthrough all the different stages.
放到用户手中 观察他们整个使用过程的不同阶段
What do they like?
他们喜欢什么？
Where do they get stuck?
他们哪里卡住了？
Do they understand what the idea is about?
他们知道创意是什么吗？
And it's important that they have and they expressed earlier on.
重要的是要让他们尽早的了解尽早的表达
>> Do I need to explain to the user what he needs to do?
我需要向用户解释他们需要做什么吗？
>> What we like to do in this stage is kind of like it's based on one of
在这个阶段 我们一般都采取一种原则
the ideas of writing, show, don't tell.
展示 但不告诉
A great design prototype should be able to stand on its own
好的设计原型应该能够自己展示自己
without too much explaining.
不需要过多的解释
Generally we'd like to set up the user and say, imagine you're shopping for
一般来说 我们会安置好客户 然后说想象下
a new product, or imagine you're looking to write the review, and
你们要购买新产品 或是你们要写评论
now tell me what you see, and now tell me what you're doing from here.
现在告诉我你们看到了什么 然后从这里开始你们要怎么做
So we ask the users questions, and ask them to imagine themselves
我们会问用户问题 让他们自己想象
solving a specific scenario, and we watch what they do.
他们要解决某个具体问题 然后观察他们会怎么做
We ask them questions to clarify, but
我们是问他们问题搞清楚他们的想法
we're not trying to sell the product to them.
而不是要把产品卖给他们
One of the mistakes that people make in this stage
在这个阶段 大家最容易犯的一个错误是
is that they imagine this is a marketing pitch and
把它当作是市场宣传
they start explaining how awesome the product is, or why they love the idea.
不断解释产品有多棒 为什么他们喜欢这个创意
This is a useful approach if you're trying to recruit that specific person
如果你是要让人购买你的产品 这是个好方法
to buy your product and they might, just because they're trying to be nice.
因为他们会想要表现得很友好
But this approach does not answer the critical question,
但这种方法没办法回答这个重要的问题
is the product any good?
产品好不好？
Like you force someone in person to buy something is very different from
你强迫谁购买产品和你创造一个受人欢迎的产品
creating something that's popular, and that works on its own.
是不同的 因为好产品自己会说话
>> That people love.
大家都喜欢的产品
>> That's right [LAUGH].
对的
>> And are users the only people I want to get in front of this prototype?
那我是不是只需要邀请用户使用原型呢？
>> Well, the user validation is one of three points in the rapid
用户确认只是快速确认过程
evaluation process.
三个方面之一
The other two points involve the business and the technology.
另外两点是业务和技术
It's really useful to test with the stakeholders of the team.
你需要对团队的利益相关者进行测试 这个会很有帮助
Is it still meeting the business goals?
它是否符合业务目标？
Is it still answering the promises that you made to investors, or
它能不能响应你给投资商做出的承诺
the goals that you have as a company?
或者公司的目的？
And if yes, fantastic, and if no, we need to go back to the drawing board.
如果可以 那非常好 但如果不可以 我们就需要重新计划
More often than not, teams are aligned with the business goals and
很多时候 团队都是符合业务目标的
the stakeholders are happy with the results.
利益相关者对结果表示满意
But if you skip the validation, they might not approve the design or
但如果你跳过确认阶段 你可能会在后期某个时间
block it at a later stage.
不批准或阻止这个设计
So, having your quick check-in with the stakeholders, even if they didn't attend
所以在这个阶段 快速地让利益相关者进行查看
the entire sprint, can be very useful at this stage.
即便他们没有参与整个冲刺 也会是非常有用的
>> Very cool.
很棒
>> Another piece that's important here is doing a technical check.
另外重要的一点是进行技术检查
A design solution that's beautiful but no one can implement, it's only so
一个设计解决方案 看着很好但却无法执行
valuable.
那就没什么价值
So what we want to do is encourage teams to check in with a technical staff.
所以我们要鼓励团队与技术人员进行检查
Is this still going the right direction in terms of feasibility?
它是否依然符合可行性要求？
And if this seems challenging, let's clarify it.
如果看着有难度 请说明以下
What are the pieces here that seems like they're going to take the longest and
在哪些小地方你们可能耗费最长的时间
how might we be able to point is designing a way that's not creating
哪种设计方式会不造成障碍
hurdles, and it's something that we can test and deliver quickly?
这是我们能快速测试和实现的东西么？
>> Okay, so what I'm hearing is we need to do three validations,
好的 所以你告诉了我 我们需要做三种确认
validate with users, validate with business stakeholders, and
与用户 与业务利益相关者
validate with technology people.
与技术人员进行确认
>> Yeah, these validations can be rather quick.
是的 这三种确认可以非常快
A user test can be 20 to 30 minutes and you can test with three or
用户测试可以在 20 或 30 分钟 你可以测试
four or five different people.
三至五名用户
For most teams, you can even test with one person, it's already a success.
对大部分团队来说 你就算只测试了一个人 已经是种成功了
The business validation can be a five to ten minute discussion, or
业务确认可以是五至十分钟的讨论
longer if the issue is very problematic.
如果有出现问题 可以延长
Or the technical validation can be similarly short, five to ten minutes.
技术确认时间很短 五至十分钟就可以了
We're doing this as a best practice.
我们通过最佳实践完成这个任务
Sort of like covering a checklist to make sure that all the possible ways in
比如说列出检查清单
which something can fail to deliver after this point are addressed.
确保解决了之后所有可能造成无法得到结果的情况
And there are also people vouching to the solution,
还有人会对解决方案非常有信心
which makes it easier to deliver afterwards.
这样之后的产出就更加容易了
>> So what could go wrong in this stage?
这一阶段容易在哪里出错？
>> That's a great question.
这个问题很好
What could go wrong is that teams can
可能出现的错误是团队对自己的解决方案太过自信
be overly confident in their own solution and skip the user testing.
跳过了用户测试
That is a common pattern that we see with teams that are new to sprinting.
这是第一次进行冲刺的团队很容易出现的问题
They think, well, we can do the user testing later.
他们认为我们可以晚点再做用户测试
It is true that the user test can be done separately from this print, but
是的 用户测试可以在冲刺以外单独进行
that is a miss.
但这会是个缺口
While the team is together and they're fresh in the space
当团队集中在一起 对所有的原型设计还保有很新的印象
of all the prototyping, it is really valuable to right away get feedback.
如果能马上得到反馈 这会非常的有价值
If you do the user test with your whole team present and
如果在创造阶段结束后你在整个团队都在的情况下立刻进行用户测试
right after the creation session, this gives the need to write any research
这样你就能够编写研究文件
documents and it keeps all the ideas fresh in their minds.
把所有的创意鲜明地留在脑海中
That makes it that much more likely that the products and
这样的话 就更容易在下一个阶段
the problems will get addressed in the next phase.
解决产品的各种问题
>> And what happens if they don't like the solution, if the users hate it?
那如果用户不喜欢这个解决方案 讨厌它 怎么办？
>> [LAUGH] Well,
恩
if the users hate solution it's a great opportunity to learn.
如果用户讨厌这个解决方案 这是学习的大好机会
We try to be humble with our designs.
我们不要对自己的设计有太强的信心
After all, we only spend two to five days working on them.
因为毕竟我们只花了两至五天的时间
We hope that the life of the company will be much longer than that, so
我们肯定希望公司的寿命比这个要长得多
those two to five days were valuable if you learn something.
如果我们学到了什么东西 这两至五天还是很有价值的
So if the users don't like something,
如果用户不喜欢什么东西
it's a great time to seek to understand again.
这是我们重新理解的大好时机
So we go back to the first way of thinking, which was let's understand.
我们需要回到最初的思维方式 让我们重新来理解
What is it that they don't like,
他们不喜欢它的什么东西
is there something that could be solved better?
有什么是可以解决可以变更好的？
Asking questions and
问问题
probing deeper into the things that users don't like is great opportunity.
然后深入探讨用户不喜欢的东西 这是很好的机会
The best time to learn if the users don't like something
最好的情况就是 在你创建原型后 大概就五天的时间
is right after you have created the prototype, into the five days.
发现用户不喜欢什么东西
And not after you spend two years of your life telling everyone you love and
而不是说在你花费了两年 告诉大家你有多喜欢这个创意
maxing out your credit card [LAUGH] this is a great idea.
并且刷光了信用卡之后 才知道
>> So in this stage,
所以在这个阶段
we take the users, we let them play with the prototype, and we listen to them.
我们会邀请用户 让他们使用原型 然后我们倾听他们的意见
>> That's right.
是的